

# Ruben Forrosuelo

# Virtual Assistant

# **ABOUT ME**

Experienced Virtual Assistant with a strong focus on optimizing file management processes, streamlining storage procedures, and safeguarding sensitive information. Diligently validates documents, conducts thorough research to address challenges, and expertly implements practical and efficient solutions. Committed to enhancing organizational efficiency and ensuring the confidentiality of critical data.

# CONTACT



+639321181326 +639165695931



ruben. for rosuelo@gmail.com











# Strengths:

\*Strong verbal and written communication skills, enabling articulate interactions with people from diverse backgrounds.

\*Displays a genuine passion for reading and is eager to engage with various reading materials.

\*Demonstrates remarkable adaptability, quickly embracing and mastering new concepts and environments.

#### **Skills:**

- \*Strong communication and interpersonal abilities.
- \*Effective time management and organizational skills.
- \*Quick adaptability to new tasks and environments.
- \*Problem-solving and resourcefulness.
- \*Tech-savviness and digital tool proficiency.
- \*Attention to detail and accuracy.
- \*Exceptional customer service and client relations.
- \*Research capabilities and information gathering.
- $\hbox{*Multitasking and task prioritization.}$

# **Personal Data:**

Age: 27 yrs. Old

Date of Birth: February 13, 1996

Gender: Male
Civil Status: Single
Height: 5'5"/167 cm
Weight: 60 Kgs.

**Address:** 429 Fatima 2<sup>nd</sup> street

Cebu City Philippines, 6000

# **Educational Background**

### TERTIARY

# School Name:

Madridejos Community College School address:

Crossing Bunakan, Madridejos, Cebu City

## Course:

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

# **Work Experienced**

### **Essential Management Team (Texas)**

Position:Executive assistantIndustry:Real State/Rental companyMonth/Year:August 2022 – April 2023

**GoTeam** (Cebu Philippines)

Account: Asure Software

Position: Payroll Specialist II
Industry: Virtual Assistant

Month/Year: July 2022 to August 2023

# RealPage Phil. (Cebu Philippines) Account: Buildium Software

Account: Buildium Software

Position: Product Support/ Accounts Receivable Specialist

Industry: Property management company

Month/Year: April 2021 – July 2022

# Concentrix CVG Inc. (Cebu Philippines)

Account: Intuit QuickBooks Payroll and Pro & Premier Support Specialist

Position: Customer Service Agent/ Technical Support/ Hiring Team (Interviewer)

Industry: Business Process Outsourcing (BPO)

Month/Year: October 2017 to April 2021

# **Qualfon Philippines Inc.** (Cebu Philippines)

Account: StraightTalk Wireless

Position:Customer Service Agent/ Technical SupportIndustry:Business Process Outsourcing (BPO)Month & Year:January 2017 – September 2017

### **Work Description:**

## **Executive Assistant (Essential Management Team)**

I was trained and assigned in vendor coordination, repairs, and follow-ups. I generate year-end owner statements and efficiently manages invoices as well as monitor repair requests, renter deposit, refunds and prepares owner draws. In addition, I also create and manage lease documents, screening applicants, and utilizing dotloop. I even develop various document templates and <u>maintains accuracy of each transaction records</u> and account balances.

### Property Management Company CSR (Buildium)

My role as an agent is to help customers with navigating the software, recording the rent payments properly, and <u>balancing the customers' ledger</u>. I also assist customers with their accounting needs, including <u>filing 1099 forms</u> for vendors and property managers.

#### **Accounts Receivable Specialist**

I am in charge of <u>managing and reconciling the payments</u> received from customers, maintaining accurate records of transactions, and ensuring that customer accounts are up-to-date and <u>properly balanced</u>.

### **Payroll Specialist**

I handle payroll processes, <u>accurately calculated wages</u>, processed payments, and maintained meticulous records, ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements and timely payroll delivery.

### **Customer Service Agent**

I render exceptional customer support, addressing inquiries and concerns with the goal of satisfying the customer, while promoting additional services to meet their needs.

### **Technical support specialists**

I provide expert troubleshooting and solutions to resolve technical issues for customers, ensuring seamless user experiences and optimal system functionality.

## **Account Hiring Team (Interviewer)**

I team up with the hiring team to conduct comprehensive interviews, assess candidates' qualifications, and contribute to the selection process for account positions.